<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Matteo Guzzo</title>
    <link>https://teoguso.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Matteo Guzzo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 15:50:57 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://teoguso.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Paste to Vim from the System Clipboard</title>
      <link>https://teoguso.github.io/blog/paste-onto-vim-from-clipboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 15:50:57 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://teoguso.github.io/blog/paste-onto-vim-from-clipboard/</guid>
      <description>Ever tried to paste something you just copied from your browser or from anywhere else on your system onto vim? As long as you still have a mouse with a middle button, all is well, but what happens when you are on a laptop or are using a smart mouse of some sort? Depending on your system configuration that could become a very challenging task.
This article explains the issues and solutions to this in great detail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Optimize your Spark Jobs</title>
      <link>https://teoguso.github.io/blog/spark-configurator/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 17:09:50 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://teoguso.github.io/blog/spark-configurator/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR: Spark executors setup is crucial to the performance of a Spark cluster. Executor parameters can be tuned to your hardware configuration in order to reach optimal usage. I built a small web app that allows you to do just that.
Spark executors Spark jobs make use of Executors, which are task-running applications, themselves running on a node of the cluster. Spark jobs are subdivided in tasks that are distributed to the executors according to the type of operations and the underlying structure of the data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://teoguso.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 22:39:50 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://teoguso.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi!
I&amp;rsquo;m Matteo. A Physicist by training, I have studied in Italy and France and obtained my PhD at the Ecole Polytechnique in France, in the field of theoretical solid-state Physics. I started a promising career in academia but soon realized I needed to do something different for a living.
After a bit of soul-searching, I turned my attention to the field of AI and started working as a freelance Data Scientist.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>